Hello, welcome to build my name is steve right-hand
machine your program manager with microsoft I've been here about twenty years now and...that time
I worked on display technologies input technologies over the last three years in particular I
...a lot of time looking at...high dpi displays and how we can make windows work better
with those devices so here today I'm going to talk about windows
ten display scaling what that is and,
...important to you so what it is just very briefly...hear a lot more about this of course
the discussion is...platform technology its baked into our low-level frameworks
...is available to all applications and
...matters to you is this technology takes a great deal of a burden off of
use individual developers...spend a lot of time
explain how that works why it works the way it does and then what's left over for you guys to do?
We're kind of a quick run-down agenda with the talks going to look like.
Just like hardware displays inform factors are an evolving technology scaling
...windows is also been evolving over the last several years and...really new stuff in windows
...to learn about so I will be spending some time talking about that and how we have
overhauled scaling system for windows ten?
...in a nutshell and forecaster
...saying later we provided...scaling system that now works the same for all
applications in windows and which works the same across all displays and
mobile and desktop skews as well...great deal uniformity and simplicity?
As a result of that work windows platform now takes a large amount of work off the back of
...developers.
It frees you up focus on something that you hear talked about a lot of this conference today...called effective pixels
and effective resolution and adaptive scaling and layout.
So, we're going to define exactly what these meeting just a moment
but they're very important subjects you'll find discussed here andprovides an...
to that later on but the purpose of this talk is kind of lay the groundwork for that by taking the hood off
...the scaling system showing you how it works why we
built the way we did and we can kind of call that display scaling
one-oh-one some of this may be familiar with some parts of maybe new
will start there and then we'll go into the changes for windows ten and
from there will kind of go back into the developer story for display scaling...windows ten.
So, just to motivate the entire discussion...more concrete terms.
Why scaling is important to you is that your application is
going to be running on a lot of diverse screens I mean a huge number of them and
...different ways different sizes different resolutions densities
in doing distances,
for example, here to screens with very different sizes?
The little one below could be a small...four-inch...the one above could be as large as
an eighty four-inch surface probe or even larger screens in the future that's
...to one ratio and size.
In terms of resolution you could be looking at a similar...very low resolution
and up to like a four-k or even a five k monitor and we know that people are starting to think about
ak devices coming soon.
So, there you're looking at what a sixty-one ratio right now and, capable growing in the future different
densitieshere things are kind of oddly inverted that surface hub device actually
is very low density about fifty dpi but a phone the high info might have
...high as five hundred dpi today and maybe that could be going as well so there's a ten-to-one
range.
Find the same to devices could be viewed very different viewing distances eighteen inches for
handheld device hundred-twenty...are more for
...unit so there's another sixty-one ratio this is
an insane diversity if you think about it from a developers perspective there's
knowing the world you want to have to target each one of these different gamut and the entire range of each one.
We provided dpi scaling or density scaling or display scaling
and abstracts much of this complexity.
For example,
one thing that you get out of it is something we called device independent or effective pixels
and these are common across all the different devices that means if you
developed those huge promise your customers will get content that
looks reasonably the same on all devices.
And, there's even a benefit here for the hardware developers in that
there's an extensible scaling solution that will support them as a build bigger or made it more dense displays in the future.
So, what does that leave for you well...really big message I've already for this once and
I'll point to some other talks on this later is it let you start thinking about doing your layout in
these effective resolutions much simpler story?
The other thing that I want to talk about in this talk is...design your bitmap assets to
so you can support these different scale factors and we'll see why you have to do that.
it's time for what I call scaling one-oh-one we have to define some of these terms I've been throwing around terms like effective
resolution and pixels and density and viewing distance let's take a look at what they actually are.
Screen resolution everybody sees if...look at...for devices on the web is how many physical,
physical pixels across or higher devices you make me talk about four-k monitor
thirty-eight forty by twenty-one sixty or low-end phone which might be four-eighty by eight
hundredthat's the screen resolution.
Usually people talk about the size not with the to dimensions
...just with the diagonal that's kind of common coming from the video industry and we all use that so here's a
diagonal five-inch phone the density is how many pixels actually fit into a niche and in the
example here we have one hundred sixty dpi...inch that would be kind of typical for
...and...higher than you...in a desktop.
So, that leads to the physical pixel that's the smallest unit on the screen
...smallest little...can be let up at a time.
And, we have here three different screens of some of them are much density
...and they have smaller.
...physical pixels this is exactly the kind of chaos we're trying to
take you away from.
And, we can do that providing by providing something we call effective pixel which is device independent and you can see this
picture is...same-size on the screen now one thing that happens along with that
...we go from the physical resolution we already talked about the screen resolution which ranges from
...fifty-four here all we have to attend yappy.
And, when we take into account the scaling any
effective pixels then those resolutions become expressed as...resolutions
...much more...range and...kind of grow as you go
...forage to five-inch...six-inch phone and kind of rational way that doesn't depend upon the density of the pickles
anymore I think you can begin to see from this y is going to be a really great thing for you when you're doing your design and layout work?
So, the...resolution is just the size of the screen...pixels
...display scaling is just that underline technology that maps
...the effective pixels into thephysical pixels.
All right so that's actually kind of a lot of overhead in order to try to make all the content look
about the same why is content size
...important let's talk about that.
So, there's a cardinal sin when you...representations that you never presented I...
But, I wanted actually present and I chart here and the relied chart can you would senior
...office and it's perfect for this because it explains exactly why content sizes
so important you can look at this and everybody can easily read the content at the top of the screen that biggie the
fp the...z so forth but by the time you get down to that.
Bottom line even without my glasses on having trouble with it so.
This is an I chart and basically shows that content sizes very important if content gets
to small your users your customers our customers can't you can't read it can't interact
with it so just as the opposition gives you this chart and then provide you with
lenz's that basically normalize the acuity your eyes to what we think kind of
the norm is for most people one thing we do in windows is we use a
dpi scaling to normalize a content so that it looks the right size for people as well.
Now the question is how big we can start
...the top the chart highly readable you only get one
were to time could slow you down a little bit so clearly you want something a
little bit smaller now we only have a complete sense now we've got a complete sentence but things are starting to
get a little bit hard-to-read so we've gained in terms of context but we've lost in terms of size
...this can go absolutely crazy if we keep going smaller and smaller sizes so in that gamut there's a
kind of tradeoff between a size it's easy-to-read and a...permit should
have enough content so you can actually read a conceptual...of information and understand it.
How do we find the right size?
Between the one extreme and the other where's the right place to tradeoff and here we have great
data from reading people in studying reading speed and, font-size is for a long-time.
And, if you take their...you graphic you can see that they're kind of two different regimes there's an
area above a certain type size in which basically reading speed is very high
in fairly consistent level clearly, you know, buy anything by increasing the
size of the...above that point on the other side of that is a regime
were reading speed falls off pretty quickly as you make type gets smaller and smaller so, for example,
a person with twenty, twenty vision can make out roughly three-point text from sixteen inches
away but that would be very slowly on this chart
that comes down to about forty words.
Per minute instead of the four hundred so that should be capable to
...a good reading size so...about ten percent of your reading speed and usually that
inflection point where we passed from one regime into the others about three times that minimum level of acuity so
what happens if we error too much in the size of sm you get
a more content but people will tend to squared they will keep their eyes open these
are just kind of involuntary responses to dealing with small things so your eyes dry out the
conference and you start having fatigue headaches so small text not only
slows you down.
But, it also increases your visual fatigue and both of these are issues for both the comfort
...the productivity of our customers.
So, we want to keep it well out of that range.
Now that's an important point here not
everybody's the same individual users have to be in control
of things for one thing as we age that curve traditionally
dress a little bit to the towards the right we begin to lose the ability to read is
quickly even with...just because our eyes are aging and even
...given age group there are different kinds of reading that people do somebody who's
just reading fictionit probably is going for speed
coder however speed is not so important it's really more import for somebody who's
doing code development to get a lot of context on the screen and he's not going to be reading coded at four hundred words
...he's going to be studying small pieces of it
so for somebody like that actually getting down on the other side of the curve where you
want to move very slowly could be an appropriate thing so we have to provide away for users to control this.
I said several times things about viewing distance I mention sixteen inches
and different distances so on why is viewing distance important this is really critical to our
platform nobody else seems to take this into account the way we try to do clearly the optimal
...well-put on-screen is going to depend upon how far away that
screeners from you remember the ietf chart if you...in the...office and he has to read aligning you
could just say excuse me and it doctor let me go check and you stood up and walked up to it I can be the
bottom line no problem the clearly you're getting around the whole point of his test and
for similar reasons when we have screens a great distance we need to make things bigger...screens that
are very close we need to make a smaller so scaling depends upon viewing distance.
As we said earlier we have a range of about eighteen two hundred twenty inches in our devices just
today sixty-one range query that's too big a range not to pay some attention too and we do a scaling.
So, our goal is the content...scale larger and...screens large and less so on closer screen
so...appears roughly the same sizes in this picture now you're going to say
yes but users still have to be able control this because perhaps I is a phone user tend to...my
phone farther away or as a desktop user maybe I tend to lean a little bit closer my screen and
that's absolutely true there's a lot of individual variation here so our solution has to also provide the way for the
individual user to change the sales scaling on each display so here are three different screens
with the same content on them and you can see that the content is actually using different scaling factors two hundred fifteen one
hundred and the content is not look the same size but that's because these devices are meant to be seen a different
viewing distances if you take that into account you can see they're starting to look like the same-size
...you actually get that vantage point you can see visually
...the same angle for everybody so that's what we're going for with this
...come back to my presentation.
So, we talked about viewing distance and why that matters which
...pretty obvious that display density has much the same impact?
If we always rented a particular fun cliff like the sm I
here to a fixed number of pixels...on devices with smaller pixels content
get smaller and here over like a roughly a five-to-one ratio if it's important
content be a certain size then we have to do something to adjust...as a number of pixels gets greater.
So, what we really want to see is a benefit that comes out of the at...height hired dpi
screens where we keep the same-size but as a number
of pixels increases we can use more pixels to render the shape more
and more precisely and this actually becomes easier to read is that as
a density goes up now in this case going past
about maybe two hundred dpi so is probably just a nice to have but another scripts
the problems can be far more severe here we have a character which has I think I
...on the order twenty-three twenty-four white and black horizontal bands just define it?
...at eleven points on a
windows desktop machine ninety-six dpi you only have fifteen pixels to work with
...vertically and there's just no way you can bring out that level of detail even
...three hundred dpi you can see look very closely that.
Some of the horizontal lines are not
define quite is crispy as others are and this just has to do with still not even if
...dpi having enough resolution to actually describe this
gift perfectly so we think there's actually quite a bit head room for...
Particularly when dealing with these kinds of far eastern fonts and, scripts.
So, this is a good time to step back and just take a look mathematically how we take all this
into account we've said we need to take account the density we need to take into account
doing distance and it's really not very complicated first we have to find out how many
pixels there are per inch...do that would just be take the resolution divided by the
with but since most people...size of the device in terms the diagonal we have to come up with an
approximate diagonal representation of the number of pixels and we can just do that using the factory and theorem so we take
the resolution the x direction and the y direction came of that first screenshot several
slides back we square then we'd add then we take the square root and we divide that by the size and that gives the density
...comes out in the dots per inch because the resolution
in x and resolution wire both dots...divide that by a size.
So, this all comes to the screen geometry we can get...information as soon as we see in display plugged in.
Now from that we extract what we call the scale factor and basically it's scale just like the
density but also scales like the viewing distance so are kind of goal standard
...reference machine is a classic windows box
running ninety-six dpi sitting on a desktop roughly twenty
eight inches away so based on that.
If we know the density and it's not ninety-six we know the viewing
distances not twenty-eight we can just take those ratios and scale
at hundred-percent by that so hundred-percent is that reference device another devices then get
larger and larger values we don't really see very many devices that fall below that even the surface hub with
...fifty...dot four-inch because it's being seen...such a large viewing
distance...up having a twenty percent scale factor.
So, you see we factor that interviewing distance and then we can go to the effective resolution which
is just the screen resolution in x and y scale down by the scale factor.
So, once again screen geometry comes in...the scale factor from the...calculation so this is how we do the work to figure out
what the scale factor should be except this is just the first step.
The...at this point is we've come up with a number which is going to be different for every display
and there are hundreds of different displays out there they don't all fall
into feature you would end up as a developer seeing dozens at least of different scale factors
...to support and dozens of different effective resolutions we haven't really solve the problem for
...if we just give it to this way we've taken away some of the degrees of freedom but we still
give you an enormous gamut stuff to try to consider so.
At the end is calculation within snap these results to what we call
...toes or buckets or...just...scale factors and even though there might be
hundreds of different percentage values between a hundred and four
hundred-percent we're only going to have a few buckets in there and everybody falls into one bucket or another it's
a rounding kind of thing so we take that computed scale factor from the previous slide we just
rounded to one of the...scale factors we can do that up or down we have
...in place where we make a decision to go either up or down.
And, then there's one last thing we also guarantee us developers a certain minimum resolution
that you, for example, on a mobile device we say you resolution never be below three twenty by
four-eighty so in order to enforce that we have to look at the result of this
computed scale factor after we bucket we look at and we say okay what is the effective resolution and
if it's less than the guarantee then we say up we got a lower the scale factor and make go for
...effective resolution so in pseudo code we
basically do a little while loop you can think of this is iterating that will just keep generating going-to
lower scale factors until we get to an effective resolution...is actually greater than or equal to the minimum guarantee.
And, those are the values we now support for windows
...this is new eight hundred six hundred is a step down from we
support for desktop but we've found this is really important for a number of sm tablets in
the seven eight-inch range that want to support desktop this gives a better experience and
phones also we're seeing on some of the smaller founded important have a smaller resolution there
...we had passed as well so the end of this means...the...scale faq you actually see on...not going to
be exactly...but the physical geometry would lead you to their
be surrounding differences this variation can be a small amount up or down.
The good news is if we have enough buckets and each
buck is not too big and the amount of variation you can have
...that buck is constrained so the size doesn't get too far out of whack and that's really been
an important goal so.
How does this really work as...I've been talking a lot here's an example?
...devices there's actually some of the same devices I showed the very beginning
the talk you can see all the diversity in terms of their size their density
thereresolution but when we had scaling to the picture this is what you see
...to the visual size of the effective pixel as measured in a kind
of a degrees.
Is amazingly close we've...within basically a ten percent up or down range more at
And, the effective resolutions are now in a much tighter gamut
than the physical resolutions are and then we have very scale factors...picked out of
...set of plato's so at the end
the scaling process we can give you an effective resolution you can use
...layout we have a scale factor that we usually get the
...framework and it does the magic scaling for you and you end up being able to
code your designed to these effective pixels and the very confident that the experience
your provide is going to look recently the same across all these devices and will work well for your customers?
Now this is scaling one-to-one we could say this about almost about any of our releases what are we done differently
in windows ten well there's one big huge thing we've unify
our scale factors for all classes of applications...platform.
We've come to a fairly simple set of
upscale factors one hundred-percent one twenty five one fifty two hundred fifty three hundred four hundred.
And, this replaces quite a bit of complexity we've had in the past.
So, there are some that exemptions there are existing apps out there for eight
...windows phone...that expect other scale factors and we have...so they will actually run as
they used to on a particular device but moving forward with all the universe
...we expect people to be coding to these up-scale factors.
Why those...a number of reasons for one thing they
rely on really well with some other app platforms that are out there in particular android
ios we thought this was really helpful...you were kind target multiple platforms
...particular application at least we should make it possible for-you to
use your assets back and forth across the different ones so are if you've already sporty android
you're already sporting most of...if...if you sporting ios even just one hundred two hundred
you've got a really good start on what you need to do for windows and I will say and we'll talk about this more
detail you don't actually have to support all of these in fact I put in bold face the ones
that we think are most important sporting we think that that's all you support...pretty good story?
So, there's the industry alignment...other issues these
...granular certainly more granular than the competition we actually think this is a good thing
especially if you don't have to provide assets these intermediate values are ability to set the platform
at the means the content size can be more tightly contain I remember I said earlier about keeping the bucket
small and close together if you look at the distance between two hundred three hundred,
for example, if you...advice fell right
...should be credit two-fifty then it's either going to be what twenty percent to
small almost twenty percent to big
...be the only options if we didn't have a two-fifty.
We have the same michigan here for the one twenty-five between one hundred and one fifty it's even conceivable in the
future that we might decide that we need to have some additional scale factors in here that we would add at some
point in the future again, it's the with the goal of keeping the content size remarkably consistent for
all your...and also with the goal for use developers you still only
have support eye-hand full-scale factors so we think
this granularity is a really good thing another big change in the past I think all of our scale factor systems top
...around two-fifty but we know four-k devices are coming and we know
...need for hundred-percent scaling within the next couple of years for some of those devices so we've built that all
we at four hundred of course we can see how that would extend
for the future when people start throwing ak devices atis.
What does this mean for you as a developer well I always like to draw that when I call appear
may chart?
We provide something in the platform this kind of a base for everything and we've already talked about that so I'm not going to go into
it anymore we give you this we come up with a scale factor effective resolution we give that to you and use a developer fall
into one of several classes...where the application pyramid most developers just
fall into the bottom area these are things that every application should be doing...a mainstream at,
for example, one thing is...the effective resolution your design and
layout this is the whole subject and I said before we got multiple talks on elsewhere again
...provide pointers on that later but for purposes of this talk we...to talk about
providing these assets for as I've already said some of the scale factors.
Now where do you go beyond that.
There are few apps...have very exacting visuals they may want provides more...the scale
factors themselves rather than relying upon the system to do scaling for them.
And, then finally there are a few applications that actually...a little bit about physical pixels I want to go into that
many detail here but just to give you an example if you...an application had put a ruler on the screen,
for example, so, you could measure things you need actually know-how big physical pixels were in order to
...how far apart space lines in the ruler there are api for that we have those api
...that onethey still exist used to use them I don't need spending more time talking about them
now but this is a relatively small case this is the big case a few developers
...more higher-quality needs around, around their assets
...have more detailed assets they can go with this and then again for just a small
handful of scenarios you might need those aps.
So, let's talk about those bitmap assets.
At this point you may be remembering if you...to some of the previous bills we had similar issues when we talk about
...phone apps in windows phone
blue and in-store apps are a lot of questions come up around bitmap assets
we have a lot of scale factors how can you support them all which scale factor should you support
directly...why not just support all of them.
What happens if the platform has to scale these...different displays...haven't provided them how can
you control which assets go to which devices and displays?
These are all really important questions and fortunately the answers is a very similar to...what
we had before so I want to go...is go into it in detail and show how to applies to the windows
timescale factors.
So, let's talk about bitmap assets.
If you only provide say one hundred-percent asset and I have to tell you about half of the
you out there are doing that today are telemetry says only fifty percent
fifty six percent of our developers...supplying more than
a hundred-percent asset what that means is that...runtime on any other devices
any of the scale factor we will do our best to stretch that
...to fit in boob give you the right size because that's our number
one goal but the quality of the scaling maybe pretty poor.
You can it's not too surprisingthis is like a thirty two by thirty two so you've only
got a thousand twenty four bits of information you're trying to stretch that out to a hundred-twenty
...you don't have the information provide a nice crispy image you just
out so this is the...can be done with in the system now I'll give you a caveat
if you actually display this on a very high-density screen
...would not be as bad as this because the pixels that are blurry
...really small but you can see the difference between this and this onto screen side-by-side.
And, what I'm telling you...half of you out there
are basically letting you develop your customers live with this kind of experience instead of crisper one?
Ok, scaling up is not really good and...sense we all understand that theoretically what
about scaling down what...beautiful if you do the same experiment you start with a
forty percent...down.
It's much better at every stage.
If you get these guys right next to each other you can sometimes see this is a
little bit better depending on the art but, in general it's a great story.
You just do that well.
The answer is we don't...you just provide big assets and there's a good reason for
Your apps maybe running on very low
...devices that don't have room for a lot of big assets.
Don't forget that...in memory?
The size of the asset...the square of the scale factor so if you're doing one hundred versus fourteen
hundred you're talking about sixteen to one ratio now in...footprint it may not be that bad
because at least this icon content tends to compress pretty well you can see you only got about
a four-to-one ratio but in order to render to on-screen you are going to have to expand
...memory so this strained eat a lot of memory at runtime.
And, this is just one very small.
...what if you had like a hundred of them.
And, what if you lead needed larger
ones you could end up with easily with ten megabytes of memory footprint
at runtime which would be fine on a very high-end device like a desktop machine or even
...in phone that's got a lot of...but you don't want to be burdening
...low-end customers have five hundred megabyte
phones with ten megabytes of data that they really don't need because...devices probably only running
...hundred-percent?
we have a solution for that the first step is you do need to provide more than one asset
...to four hundred for the...devices media one
...low-end and we found out and practice having one in the middle is a good idea too.
...by itself is still not enough because you're still now you're
...people hundred two hundred four hundred all the time so the other part of it is use
asset packages and this is a technology that means that your users only download
scale factors they actually neo their devices that's not a new technology but
right now telemetry says only about nineteen percent of our developers are using this.
So, this is a really important thing we want people to...and study...how to use properly.
let's talk a little bit about the runtime how that's manage asset selection and where these asset
...fall into it so there's a technology called mit
modern resource technology I think it's what it stands for and it's basically a technology that
manages assets...various kinds...strings but,
maps that kind of thing?
As a selection mechanism
is driven by resource naming so in the case of scaling if you
had an asset lined friendly, friendly name dot ping you would just generate versions names
...the name scale dash one hundred scale dash two hundred so forth and just
named in that way and that is enough for the windows runtime to pick them out
and treat them as different variance different scale factors for the same asset and in
your code you just use the friendly name dot ping you don't have to address the scale factor at all.
And, that runtime the runtime will pick the best available version look in your assets folder
...I see a one and two and a four hundred and I'm running at say
...I will pick the two hundred and that's the best one is
available and I will if I need to our bitmap scale it down to fit and results should be pretty good
what is best actually mean here well I don't want to go into the exact heuristics,
heuristics do favor down scaling over udp scaling as they should and they do
...being closer over farther the upshot is that
if you actually specify the one hundred two hundred four hundred this is what will happen at runtime
...use the four hundred down scaled two-fifty and maybe up to the future we use a two hundred
down scaled one twenty-five...use the one hundred for one hundred and results of that look very good.
Okay, so, you generated your one hundred two hundred four hundred what is this asset
...thing this is what's really important and asset
...is just a way of building your
...your application in visual studio that generates the application and it
also makes available to the store asset
...that each contain the assets for particular scale factor now this
mit technology is not as I said earlier just about scale...is a great way to manage
...localize will strings as well you can have you different locales...in different
...and the nice thing about that is that at runtime or at
...time when I when I have an app and I get from the store to store basically
looked at my client machine it says something like your english.
You don't need high contrast names ...you're
...the normal theme.
you've got a hundred fifty percent scaling so I'll give you any hundred-fifty percent assets I can
Failing that I'll give you two hundred failing
...four...give you one hundred...give you the best selection and...can
find out of whatever the developer...provided and it will download those to my machine.
Now you may ask well when I multiply on I've got a one hundred-percent display
...display.
The answers very simple
...detect both of those let's build send you all of those.
Here the skeptical voices what about if I had a display later on the
different scale factor that's actually covered too let's say that I've only got
...percent asset on my machine here and I end up
...that to a low density monitor...hundred-percent would be more appropriate or the other way around which
be even more important I only had one percent asset I connected high-density monitor I would really like
...nice chris presentation what will happen at that instant you'll just have you
one hundred-percent asset the system will scale it up...hundred-percent but
...will also kind of put check mark...there saying well you've,
you've got a...hundred-percent scale factor you could use now and, they're actually is one of the store
I see it so let me mark your application is suitable for update.
And, the next time you go to update your application which you may notice right away
...notification center what you'll get is actually not a code update but you'll get the new asset you need not
have a crisper experience and that device in the future.
That's the asset...technology that's the
...only twenty percent of our developers...today we really everybody picking up on this
and taking advantage of it so
...might come back to now that question of one hundred two hundred four hundred tell you what that buys you we think one
hundred-percent is definitely the starting point is in fact the default so if you don't do
something extraordinary visual studio when it goes to build your application will say wait you don't have a one
hundred-percent for this and you have to actually go into the manifest make changes if you don't want to provide one
hundred-percent and it makes sense because eighty five percent of our desktop devices are still
running hundred-percent today even with the high dpi devices that are coming there's a lot of
legacy hardware out there and they're still the low-end the cheapest thing you can...
Some of the new low-end tablets are also falling into that space phones are not
...that space phone started around hundred-fifty maybe a few hundred
...five but this you can see is going to be a huge number of devices.
Number two I think priorities twenty percent because then that gives you great down scaling coverage
...dpi desktops...traditionally or hundred-twenty five.
Two-fifty.
Of...one fifty two hundred maybe even
...two hundred...be pretty good results.
also by the same token give you really good coverage for most of the phones are likely to run on that are...higher
meet the running...hundred-twenty five alway...percent but then we think the third one forty percent
is really important for future proofing because we already know acuity phones are here.
And, the four-k tablets are coming and they'll be down
...fairly small sizes and by the way when you do that it also
improve some of these high-end devices that are already out there it's better than the...hundred-percent for those.
So, we really think these are the three importance and to nail and get right.
And, by the way if you
porting from and ios app you've already got these two.
And, if you reporting from android you probably have all three.
That is unless you...only delivering ios and android one hundred-percent assets so
now's the time to get out of that fifty-six percent of our developers and,
start providing better assets we also have telemetry data that says about forty three percent
of our users notice scale-up assets in use and find them ugly
not a good look at so as a huge number of users that
you could be making quite a bit happier by providing these higher levels of assets.
And, this would be saying...up your after success against your competitors if you're
reluctant to do that first at least keep an eye out for feedback and see if people are complaining about
...visuals and if you start to see that take...a as assigned you need upgrade your assets.
Here's an interesting table just tells you kind of some sample...examples of
...devices that would actually follies various categories and kind of
a sense and how they how they look abstractly I won't talk to that...a good thing
to look at what's kind of nice is if you stick with our one hundred twenty percent for hundred-percent device
advice you can see how what kind of coverage you get from each one of the scale factors?
Okay, so.
We want you to make one hundred twenty four percent assets.
How do you know-how big to make them I mean if you're going to author asset you're probably working in some kind of
...physical pixel space you really want to make you want the what the twitter and
...for example, exactly the right physical size to take up that
many pixels so it doesn't have any stretching by the runtime so this
...now even though we've sort of told you do everything
...pixels you have to worry about actual pixels not really
...as a designer you should still be starting with your effective pixel
ui layout because the size and effective pixels is actually the one
hundred-percent physical size you need to target so if
...if you if you wanted have a three hundred...effective pixel
icahn or picture of some kind then that you want...size?
And, due to represent size is going to double that you forty percent size quadruple that so the
math is very easy nothing hard to worry about you don't need to know about what the actual size are going-to be at runtime
you just need to know I...to be three-by-three...effective pixels and these are the size you need author.
...a quick moment here to skip over and just show.
...and bs.
And, use different machine for this is almost
a no-brainer of an app I basically took a new project
system that bs study new project I went into the
main panel and you can see where the where the default grid was I just
...image.
And, I gave it a source name assets sampled...bing.
And, I moved around a little bit...where I wanted it and then over here
in the assets file you can see I've got sample that scaled dash one hundred scale gestures
...four hundred so I created those offline just using a bitmap
editors really and dumping here and immediately bs knows
...knows how to connect those because it's got the mit technology built-in
...collecting into that so you're seeing actually the for hundred-percent scale now why we...community
...answer is that in my designer I...to pick this particular capability for
the drop down so this would be a five-inch phone tend earphone which will default to three
percent scaling so since I'm providing one-two and for the best twitter three hundred is
...down scale from four hundred that's what I...would do it runtime and that's what...showing here.
And, you can see very easily that if I were to switches to...
...hundred-percent scale device that what...not
...one hundred scaling so.
It's kind of interesting actually you can just as further proof that you don't need to have all these scale
factors.
Two-fifty I still using the four hundred.
You really can't tell visually that's being down scale but it is on-the-fly so.
So, that's really all there is to this it's very easy the
it's almost a intuitive in terms of dumping things and having the named appropriately
connecting them up and again the only connective tissue there was having.
Having the source name.
Assets...slash sample...
please study this make sure you get this into all your applications the word about asset authoring
in the demo I just showed you I just used to bitmap editor the...
Open-source kind of thing that anybody can get their hands-on didn't do a
lot of work in real-life course you probably have more...higher artistic
...you're striving for with your assets we would ask you to use vector assets whenever possible there
are number reasons why.
They give you a...quality artwork at any scale factor so if you got something looks really good.
It's probably going to...any scale fact...out and it's very
easy to do that so in fact you may want to just go ahead and support all the scale factor
you a at the very beginning it gives you the most control over the way things look if you
...do that...you sort of fitted that second-stage on the pyramid.
It's also easy to come back to later on
you just imagine you put your app it's selling well.
But, there's a barrier towards in europe because you need...versions and unfortunately
your art work has some that localize text.
Well, if you use decked design tools you just go back in there and you at the strings and
you put them out and use them...organize them as both scale factor and
language depended assets and you're done so that's a lot easier than having to work with bitmap
editors if you are using bitmap art tooling them
our recommendation be start with a hundred-percent because it's a lot easier to scale that down and
...blow it up and try to crisper up you'll end up catching a lot more pixels if you do with the other way around.
And, if by using vector design tools like adobe illustrator like they're
already all kinds of scripts out there for android and like that...you just
...base spit out all the scale effect you need support.
Let me sum up here you kind of the call the action.
We want to see assets at a hundred two hundred forty percent in
all applications not just fifty-six percent we think this is the right way going forward
...put you in a great place to be future proof for future devices and
it'll give you a great experience on all the existing devices we also want to users asset
...because really important to be taking up a minimal footprint specially on
lower and devices it's easy to do
and only twenty percent of use or using it now so learn more about that.
That will take care of all the asset work.
Then the bigger thing is go often...of these are the talks because we're going to spend a lot of time talking about now
...doing scaling for you and we're getting these effective pixels effective
resolutions how do you do your layout how do you handle changes
...resolution as...as an application moves from one display to another or is
deploys on different devices and there's a whole set of talks here with different
levels of detail about this...very-high-level some are very design focused but I think they're all excellent
and...more information...that there?
So, that's what we're asking for take off-beat this big bite with the effective resolution
effective pixel work and do us take a step up here in the bitmap
...getting a better experience...our customers all right
thanks very much I hope this is helpful to you and look for the...you again?